polycom.com 2017-12-16

# Privacy Policy - Polycom, Inc.

**POLYCOM**

**Effective Date: June 11, 2012  
Last Modified Date: April 11, 2016**

**Your Privacy**

At Polycom, we are committed to respecting your privacy. We recognize that when you choose to provide us with information about yourself through our “Products” and “Services,” you trust us to act in a responsible manner. That’s why we have put a policy in place to protect your Personal Information. This statement describes (1) the types of Personal Information we collect, (2) how we use and protect this information, and (3) who we disclose it to.

The “ ** _Products_** ” include the software and hardware we sell or license to our customers.  Unlike Services, our customers implement Products within their own infrastructure.

The “ ** _Services_** ” means any website, mobile application, or Internet service under the control of Polycom, Inc., whether partial or otherwise, in connection with providing an online platform for Polycom’s services and other services provided by Polycom.

 “ ** _Personal Information_** ” means information that alone or when in combination with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you, such as: name, address, email address, or phone number. We do not consider Personal Information to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not allow a third party to easily identify a specific individual.

**What information does Polycom collect?**

In general, we collect Personal Information from you when you voluntarily provide it by: (1) providing information to us or our business partners in connection with a transaction or in furtherance of our business relationships; (2) registering products on our website or otherwise contacting us to obtain information relating to our products or our services; (3) signing up to enter a promotion, participate in an event or survey, receive newsletters or other literature; or (4) providing information when we (i.e. our customer service representatives or employees) contact you either at trade events or by other means such as email or phone.

In some cases we collect this information from you directly and we may also receive such information from our business partners (such as resellers) who may collect this information from you in the context of your business relationship with us and/or the business partner.

In connection with these activities, we may collect Personal Information, including, but not limited to, your name, business address, email address, telephone number, fax number, and other contact information, user name and/or password associated with the use of our Services, occupation, company name, name of position within company, the type of product you are seeking, the type and number of products you and your business purchase, and other information necessary to conduct business with you or which we, or our business partners may ask you to provide.

We may also collect/obtain certain non-Personal Information from you including, but not limited to, your browser type (e.g., Netscape or Internet Explorer), operating system (e.g., Windows or Macintosh), Internet service provider, IP address, websites visited,  the domain name from which you accessed the Services (e.g., yahoo.com), how you use and interact with our Products (for example, we collect information about the related hardware, technical configurations, settings, licenses, versions), and meta-data about how you use the Product, (such as the length of usernames and passwords (but never the content)).

Our Services may use standard technologies, such as “cookies”, web beacons and other HTML tools, to collect information about how you use the Services or to record that you opened an email marketing message. Polycom may also use customized links or other similar technologies to track email links that you click. We may associate that information with your Personal Information in order to provide you more focused service communications. Please go to What are “cookies” and web beacons? below for more information.  **How do we use this information?**

Polycom may use this information for general purposes including:

(1) to fulfil your requests for certain products and services, (2) to conduct business with you (including obtaining and disclosing credit and billing information), (3) to correspond with you regarding orders, process a credit card order, or deliver a product, (4) to perform credit fraud screening services for transactions between you and us and/or others (5) to administer promotional offers, contests or other promotional events and notify winners (6) to keep you up to date on the latest product and services announcements and to provide you with other information we think you would like to hear about either from us or from our Polycom business partners (although if you tell us that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes), (6) to send you emails containing information about our products and services that we think may be of interest to you if you have indicated that you wish to receive such information by email (each such e-mail communication includes an unsubscribe link allowing you to opt-out of receiving further communications of that type); and (7) to better understand your needs and provide you with better Products and Services.

In addition we may use the information collected (1) to personalize your experience on our Services, (2) to conduct internal reviews of our Services and to help us better understand  use of our Services, (3) to help us improve the design and layout of our Services and provide content of interest to you, (4) conduct internal Product reviews and to help us better understand how customers use our Products, and (5) help us improve the Products.

If you do not provide us with your personal information, we may be unable to provide you with some or all of the Services.

**Who do we disclose this information to?**

We share your information with our business partners, service vendors, authorized third party agents and contractors, your organization’s account administrators, and Polycom affiliates for the purposes mentioned above.

Because Polycom operates globally your information may be transferred to other countries for any of the purposes described above. In particular we may transfer some of your information to be held and processed on our behalf for the abovementioned purposes by third parties in the United States and in other countries.

Polycom may also retain and disclose Personal Information as allowed or required by applicable law, including making disclosures that are necessary or advisable to: (a) protect the rights, safety or property of users of our Products and Services, the public, or Polycom or our suppliers; and (b) conform to legal or regulatory requirements.

Polycom will not trade, sell or rent your Personal Information although we may disclose your information in connection with a sale or disposal of all or part of the Polycom business. Polycom may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will not include any Personal Information.

**How does Polycom protect your information?**

We take steps in accordance with good industry practice to protect the information we collect from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Polycom safeguards the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures and your Polycom account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. We do not provide any representation for the security of third-party websites, products and services used in conjunction with Products and Services.

By using the Products and Services or providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Products and Services. If we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Services or sending an email to you. You may have a legal right to receive this notice in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice), please notify us at [privacy@polycom.com](mailto:privacy@polycom.com).

**What are “cookies” and web beacons?**

“Cookies” are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive which enables us to recognize your computer when you return to our Services. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that may be used to track the pages you have visited on our Services. Our cookies enable us to provide you with a more personal service.

A web beacon is an electronic image, called a single-pixel (1x1) or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on a user’s computer, such as a user’s cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page where the web beacon is placed. Some Web beacons may be unusable if you elect to reject their associated cookies.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our Services or via HTML-formatted emails, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, although you may not be able to take full advantage of our Services if you do so.

**Your Consent**

By using our Products and Services and/or by disclosing information to us or our business partners in furtherance of our business relationships with you, you are accepting and agreeing to the practices described in this Privacy Statement.

If we decide to change our privacy practices, we will post those changes in a revised Privacy Policy so that you are kept informed of what data we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. Please check our Privacy Policy for changes from time to time to make sure you are aware of our latest privacy practices.

**Your Ability to Access, Update or Remove Your Information**

If you would like to access or change any of your Personal Information which we hold please email us at [privacy@polycom.com](mailto:privacy@polycom.com). You may also request the removal or correction of your Personal Information held by us by sending an email to the same address. You can review the Product documentation for the specific Product you use to learn more about your choices with regard Product data collection. If you choose to remove your information, we may retain some Personal Information to the extent required to prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, enforce [Polycom’s Services Terms and Conditions](http://www.polycom.com/products-services/services/services-terms-and-conditions.html), respect your opt-out preferences, and comply with legal requirements as permitted by law.

**Children and Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information from children under 13 years of age, and no part of the Products or Services are directed to children under the age of 13. If you learn that your child has provided us with Personal Information without your consent, you may alert us at [privacy@polycom.com](mailto:privacy@polycom.com). If we learn that we have collected any Personal Information from children under 13, we will promptly take steps to delete such information and terminate the child’s account.

**Safe Harbor**

With respect to the personal data it receives from countries in the European Economic Area and Switzerland, Polycom complies with, and has certified its adherence to, the Safe Harbor Principles as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce, as agreed upon with the European Commission and the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland, which can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>. To view our Safe Harbor Policy, please check our certification at <https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx> or email [safeharbor@polycom.com](mailto:safeharbor@polycom.com) to request a copy.

ADVISORY: On October 6, 2015, the European Court of Justice issued a judgment declaring as “invalid” the European Commission’s Decision 2000/520/EC of 26 July 2000 “on the adequacy of the protection provided by the safe harbor privacy principles and related frequently asked questions issued by the US Department of Commerce.”  In response to this decision, the Department of Commerce announced that it will continue to administer the Safe Harbor program, including processing submissions for self-certification to the Safe Harbor Framework.  We intend to maintain a Safe Harbor Certification; please be advised, however, that due to the ECJ’s decision, we may be required to undertake additional steps, such as entering into European Commission (EC) Model Contract Clauses.  For business customers impacted by this recent decision who are seeking an alternate compliance basis for EU-U.S. personal data transfers, please contact us by submitting an email to [safeharbor@polycom.com](mailto:safeharbor@polycom.com).

**Tell us what you think**

Our goal is to respect your privacy. To help us improve our privacy policies, please give us your feedback. We welcome your comments and questions. Send these to [privacy@polycom.com](mailto:privacy@polycom.com).

**Complaints [FOR AUSTRALIA ONLY]**

If you are concerned that we have breached this policy or the privacy laws in Australia, you may lodge a complaint by sending an email to [privacy@polycom.com](mailto:privacy@polycom.com).

Please provide us with specific details regarding your complaint together with any supporting evidence.

We will investigate the issue and determine the steps that are needed to resolve your complaint appropriately. We will contact you if we require any additional information from you and will notify you in writing of the outcome of the investigation.

If you are not satisfied with our determination, you may contact us at [privacy@polycom.com](mailto:privacy@polycom.com) to discuss your concerns or contact your local privacy or data protection authority.
